window.__examLoadCallback({
  "title": "Computer_Network - Computer_Network — Slot 12 (15 Questions)",
  "duration": 42,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "Computer_Network — Slot 12",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>Which one of the following is TRUE about the interior gateway routing protocols - Routing\nInformation Protocol (RIP) and Open Shortest Path First (OSPF)? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>RIP uses distance vector routing and OSPF uses link state routing</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>OSPF uses distance vector routing and RIP uses link state routing</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Both RIP and OSPF use link state routing</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Both RIP and OSPF use distance vector routing</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>RIP uses distance vector routing and OSPF uses link state routing</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1981/gate2014-2-23#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>Consider a selective repeat sliding window protocol that uses a frame size of 1 KB to send\ndata on a 1.5 Mbps link with a one-way latency of 50 msec. To achieve a link utilization of\n60%, the minimum number of bits required to represent the sequence number field is ________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "5",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1795/gate2014-1-28#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>Let the size of congestion window of a TCP connection be 32 KB when a timeout occurs. The round trip time of the connection is 100 msec and the maximum segment size used is 2kB. The time taken (in msec) by the TCP connection to get back to 32KB congestion window is ______ <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "1100",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1794/gate2014-1-27#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>Consider a token ring network with a length of 2km having 10 stations including a monitoring station. The propagation speed of the signal is 2x\\(10^{8}\\) m/s and the token transmission time is ignored. If each station is allowed to hold the token for 2 \\(\\mu\\)sec, the minimum time for which the monitoring station should wait (in \\(\\mu\\)sec) before assuming that the token is lost is _______. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "28",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1793/gate2014-1-26#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>Identify the correct order in which the following actions take place in an interaction between\na web browser and a web server. <br>\n1. The web browser requests a webpage using HTTP. <br>\n2. The web browser establishes a TCP connection with the web server. <br>\n3. The web server sends the requested webpage using HTTP.<br>\n4. The web browser resolves the domain name using DNS. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>4,2,1,3</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>1,2,3,4</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>4,1,2,3</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>2,4,1,3</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>4,2,1,3</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1792/gate2014-1-25#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>Which one of the following are used to generate a message digest by the network security\nprotocols? <br>(P) RSA <br>(Q) SHA-1 <br>(R) DES <br>(S) MD5 <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>P and R only</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Q and R only</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Q and S only</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>R and S only</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>Q and S only</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1791/gate2014-1-24#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following three statements about link state and distance vector routing protocols,\nfor a large network with 500 network nodes and 4000 links <br>\n[S1] The computational overhead in link state protocols is higher than in distance vector\nprotocols. <br>\n[S2] A distance vector protocol (with split horizon) avoids persistent routing loops, but not\na link state protocol. <br>\n[S3] After a topology change, a link state protocol will converge faster than a distance\nvector protocol. <br>\nWhich one of the following is correct about S1, S2, and S3? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2014 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>S1, S2, and S3 are all true</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>S1, S2, and S3 are all false.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>S1 and S2 are true, but S3 is false</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>S1 and S3 are true, but S2 is false.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>S1 and S3 are true, but S2 is false.</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/1790/gate2014-1-23#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>The protocol data unit for the transport layer in the internet stack is <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2013)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Segment</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Message</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Datagram</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Frame</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>Segment</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/44154/isro-2013-47\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following encryption algorithms is based on the Feistal structure? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2013)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Advanced Encryption Standard</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>RSA public key cryptographic algorithm</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Data Encryption standard</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>RC4</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>Data Encryption standard</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/44152/isro-2013-46\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>A packet filtering firewall can <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2013)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Deny certain users from accessing a service</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Block worms and viruses from entering the network</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Disallow some files from being accessed through FTP</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Block some hosts from accessing the network</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>Block some hosts from accessing the network</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/43986/isro-2013-45\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>Which algorithm is used to shape the bursty traffic into a fixed rate traffic by averaging the data rate? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2013)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Solid bucket algorithm</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Spanning tree algorithm</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Hocken helm algorithm</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Leaky bucket algorithm</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>Leaky bucket algorithm</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/43985/isro-2013-44\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>What is IP class and number of sub-networks if the subnet mask is 255.224.0.0? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2013)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Class A, 3</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Class A, 8</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Class B, 3</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Class B, 32</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>Class A, 8</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/43984/isro-2013-43\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>IPv6 does not support which of the following addressing modes? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2013)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Unicast addressing</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Multicast addressing</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Broadcast addressing</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Anycast addressing</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>Broadcast addressing</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/43982/isro-2013-42\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>What will be the efficiency of a Stop and Wait protocol, if the transmission time for a frame is 20ns and the propagation time is 30ns? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2013)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>20%</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>25%</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>40%</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>66%</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>25%</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/43981/isro-2013-41\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>If the frame to be transmitted is 1101011011 and the CRC polynomial to be used for generating checksum is \\(x^{4}+x+1\\), than what is the transmitted frame? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2013)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>11010110111011</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>11010110111101</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>11010110111110</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>11010110111001</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>11010110111110</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/43979/isro-2013-40\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
});
